<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-basketball</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1893-04-01/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Game+Indoor+Sport</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOW FOR A NEW GAME
        Basketball in Carroll Institute Gymnasium.

        A GAME ALL CAN PLAY.

        Popular Diversion at Practice - A Combination of Lacrosse and Foot Ball - No Need for Roughness -
        A Sport Requiring Judgment - The Rules of the Game.

        An indoor sport which is new to this city has been introduced by Mr. Maurice A. Joyce, the athletic
        instructor at the Carroll Institute. The game has met with great popularity in other places where it has
        been played, and from the interest which it has excited among the members of the Carroll Institute it bids
        fair to meet with the success here that it has in other cities. Almost every night basket ball is played in
        the gymnasium of the institute, and the sport is not only healthy and invigorating, but exciting and full
        of interest.

        Basket ball was first started about a year ago and since that time it has spread throughout the country
        especially in the gymnasiums of the Young Men's Christian associations. It is particularly adaptable to
        business men, as little practice is required to learn it and there is no incident roughness if the rules
        are strictly adhered to. It is the intention of Mr. Joyce to try to have other teams formed in the gymnasiums
        in the city and to have regular contests between them. It commends itself in that it can be played in almost
        any sized room upon any kind of lot, whether it be large or small, and that the number of players need only
        be limited by the size of the ground. It brings into play all muscles of the body, thus being a healthy
        exercise, and at the same time the evils incident to most sports are wanting. The only apparatus necessary for
        the game to be played is a regular Rugby foot ball and two half-bushel baskets.

        HOW IT IS PLAYED

        Through the courtesy of Mr. Joyce a Star reporter witnessed a game of basket ball played at the Carroll
        Institute on one of the evenings of this week. The two baskets are attached to the ceiling track at the
        opposite ends of the gymnasium and the object of the game is to throw the ball in the opponent's basket.
        The teams consist of nine men each, made up of a goalkeeper, two backs to assist him, a center, a right
        and left center, two forwards and a home man. They are arranged in this order from the goal which they are
        defending. It is not necessary that the players should remain in their places, but they should move in such
        a way as to give the forward player an opportunity to get a good toss at the goal or the backs to keep their
        opponents from obtaining the same by taking it from them when they are about to throw. It is the duty of the
        goalkeeper to keep the ball away from the vicinity of goal, and it is more often necessary for him to bat the
        ball with his hand than for other members of the team to do so.

        [Article continues with rules and advantages of the game, including details about scoring, fouls, and team play strategy.]
    </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86088296/1893-06-01/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+Sport+Indoor</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE GAME OF BASKET BALL

        Interesting and Exciting Sport For Those Not Able to Exercise Regularly.

        The announcement that at a woman's educational institution not far from this city the students played a close
        and exciting game of "basket ball" was perhaps the first item which attracted public attention to a sport that
        is rapidly becoming very popular in this country among those who have neither the physique nor the taste for
        baseball or football. The rules of the new sport are comparatively simple, and the ease with which the
        fundamental laws of the game can be acquired in a few minutes' practice have served to make it popular wherever
        it has been introduced, while its freedom from much of the roughness and intricacy of football has also tended
        to make the devotees of basket ball enthusiastic in their praise of its merits.

        The name "basket ball" is derived from the fact that scores are made not by carrying the ball across the goal
        lines or kicking it over the goal bar as in football, but by throwing the spheroid into a moderately small
        basket, which is hung about 10 feet above the ground or floor. To accomplish such a feat usually requires much
        practice, and as a rule the try at goals are far more numerous than the scores. Either hand or both hands can
        be used in holding the ball, and it must either be thrown or be batted with the open hand - a punch with the
        fist or arm, or a kick, constituting a foul.

        The game differs from football also in the fact that no player is allowed to run with the ball, but must stand
        where it is caught, and a fair catch can be made only with the hands. If the ball is held for an unnecessarily
        long time, the umpire takes possession of it and puts it "in play" by throwing it in the air, no player being
        allowed to touch it in such an event until it has struck the ground.

        If a ball goes out of bounds, it is put in play as in football, and no player is "offside," but every player
        has the right to touch the ball anywhere or everywhere in the game, provided the ball is in play. No pushing,
        tripping, shoving or tackling is allowed, and every such offense constitutes a foul, which gives one point to
        the opposing nine. As a goal counts but three points and a foul one, there is every incentive to avoid rough
        play. The players advance the ball by tossing it to some member of their own nine, and there is the best
        opportunity for success in personal skill combined with good team play. The "forwards" and "centers" usually
        toss the ball forward, but when it gets dangerously near his own goal, the goalkeeper often bats it with the
        open palm.

        One advantage which basket ball has over many other forms of popular sport lies in the fact that, while it
        allows 18 players to participate, it can be pursued the year round in the open air during the warmer months
        and in the gymnasium while cold weather prevails. Again, basket ball can be played by persons whose physique
        is not of the most robust type, although many athletes also have found in it a healthful form of exercise.
        It has proved of great value in furnishing exercise for business men, women and children, as well as brawny
        students, and from the general success it has already attained wherever it has been introduced there is every
        probability that basket ball will soon become a very popular and widespread form of outdoor and indoor sport.
    </text>
      </result>
      <result>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1894-11-25/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Sport+Game+Indoor+Outdoor </id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>BASKET BALL THANKSGIVING GAME BETWEEN SOPHOMORES AND FRESHMEN

            Popular and Graceful Game That Has Found Great Favor Among Girls - Some of the Rules and Regulations
            Observed in Playing It

            Basket ball is to the women's college what football is to the men's. The Bryn Mawr girls are particularly
            enthusiastic over this sport, and the Smith college students are in training for a match game some day
            Thanksgiving week. A picked nine from the sophomore class will be pitted against a picked nine from the
            freshmen class. The Smith college girl is immensely interested in basket ball, which she also calls cradle
            ball.

            At Bryn Mawr the students are equally as devoted to this game; indeed their interest in it is tremendous
            and vies with 5 o'clock teas and theatricals in mitigating the ennui of varsity life. The freshman and
            sophomore classes are particularly alive to this sport. Miss Elsa Bowman is the captain of the sophomores
            nine, while Miss Corinne Putnam is the leader of the freshman.

            WHY THE GAME IS POPULAR

            The beauty of the game—or one of its beauties, for it has many—is that it can be played by any number, and
            the more the merrier it is usually voted. The ideal number, however, is nine on each side. There is a goal
            keeper, two backs to assist, a center, a right and left center, two forwards and a home man
            (i.e., a woman in this case).

            The end and aim of the game is to toss a ball, which is the size of a small football, into one of the two
            large baskets suspended at each end of the field. The winning side is the one that lands the ball in the
            opponent's basket. The basket is placed about ten feet high. When the game is played in the gymnasium the
            basket is bracketed to the side of the wall. For outdoor use it is supported at the same height by an
            upright post. The price of the baskets or goals is $15 per pair for indoor use; when supplied with a pipe
            or post for outdoors, the cost is somewhat more. The balls, which are covered with leather and about
            twenty-four inches in circumference, cost about $3 each; a rubber-coated ball can be purchased for $1.15.

            Basket ball can be played in a gymnasium, in a large room, or a small field or a large field;
            if in the latter, as many as thirty or fifty players may take part.

            APPROPRIATED BY WOMEN

            The man who originated the game, or invented it, or whatever the proper word may be,
            did not intend it merely for amusement; his idea was to provide a good all-around physical exercise,
            and as such it cannot be improved upon, combining as it does running, jumping, bending and twisting—nearly
            every muscle and joint in the body is brought into exercise.

            Mr. James Naismith of Springfield, Mass., originated basket ball about three years ago. As soon as it
            became known among the gymnasiums it spread like an epidemic. Primarily intended for young men, for whom
            most of the good things of life are intended, it was soon taken up by young women who declared that if
            there was anything good in the game they would like to become acquainted with it.

            The girls forthwith bought a book of rules, which they mastered in very brief order, donned their
            gymnasium costumes and began playing at once. The fine points of the game, however, were only acquired
            by practice.

            RULES OBSERVED

            The three players who are designated as forwards occupy the third of the ground nearest the opponent's goal;
            the centers occupy the middle third and the backs the defensive third of the ground. The forwards of one
            team stand near the backs of the other.

            Out of doors with plenty of room the field may be 150 feet long, the goal lines running through the
            baskets perpendicular to the length of the field, the side boundaries 100 feet apart. The ball is put in
            play by the referee throwing it up in the middle of the field; this is done at the commencement of the game,
            at the beginning of the second half, after each goal, and when a foul has been made. The time of play is
            two halves of twenty minutes each.

            A goal is made when the ball is thrown or batted from the ground into the basket, provided it stays in. It
            is a foul if the ball is struck with the fists or kicked. </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1895-11-26/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Play+Games+Game+Foot+Sport</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-12-18/ed-1/?sp=18&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Game+K+U+Naismith+Sport+Team</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>BASKET BALL AT K.U.

                LAWRENCE, KAS., Dec. 17.-(Special)
                The basket ball "fever" has broken out in its most violent form among Kansas university people.
                Dr. Naismith, the new physical director, brought the germs with him, and that they were healthy
                specimens is evidenced by their activity.

                At first only a few of the students saw in basket ball the diversion. But the disease spread rapidly.
                Not only does each class already possess its basket ball team, but the literary and the scientific
                men of the faculty are backing their "crack fives." Every evening the gymnasium is filled with a
                scrambling mass of humanity, and the spectators who can recognize a friend or acquaintance in the
                melee must be gifted with second sight.

                Five men compose a team at basket ball. The floor is divided into three parts. The center men of the
                playing teams occupy a space chalked off in the middle, and the other four dispose themselves in
                various graceful attitudes in the end sections. The referee tosses up the ball just above the heads
                of the centers, who are standing face to face. Each makes a jump and endeavors to hit the ball,
                knocking it over to his own men and toward his goal. Then, the scramble begins. The accomplished
                and gentlemanly contortionist in the patent medicine show could not rival basket ball players in the
                way of tying French knots in their corporal systems. The mass of writhing humanity turns over and over
                in kaleidoscopic fashion, suddenly unwinds itself and is again resolved into parts. A man goes diving
                after the ball and comes triumphantly up out of the fray with his arms full of another man's head!

                The aim in playing basket ball, so it is claimed, is to throw the ball into the round baskets, suspended
                at each end of the field, a greater number of times than the opposing players. In reality, however, it
                would seem that the cherished object of each player was to make as large and choice collection of
                bruises as possible.

                But that is basket ball from the spectator's point of view. To the players it is an all absorbing sport.
                Some of them even have the audacity to assert that it is a "gentle game, don't you know."
                Gentle, indeed! One might as appropriately speak of a bucking broncho as "well-mannered."

                When the field is not divided into sections the game is really rough, but if the chalk lines are drawn,
                and fouls are faithfully called whenever a man over-steps his boundaries, the bruise hunter adds to
                his collection more slowly. It is amusing to watch the players trying to remember to have the proper
                respect for the boundaries. Indeed it is truly pathetic to see what limitations of power a simple
                chalk line can put on these great, strong athletes. In actual agony they hang over the edge and
                reach out helpless, longing arms toward the ball. Now and then an unruly foot goes across the line,
                and then the sharp whistle of the referee is heard. A foul entitles the players on the other side a
                chance at throwing goal.

                The game consists of two halves of twenty minutes each. A twenty minute rest is given between, and a
                new team put on to utilize the rest time. Each time the ball goes into the basket two points are scored
                for the side whose goal is thrown. As in baseball, a small score indicates a good game.

                The Inventor of Basket Ball

                Dr. James Naismith is the inventor of basket ball. Unlike most of our games it is not the development
                of some medieval sport. It was worked out on scientific principles to meet a long felt want.
                Dr. Naismith was physical director of a Y.M.C.A. training school at Springfield, Mass., where the
                problem of supplying this need was brought to him for solution. Basket ball was the result.
                It was in the winter of '91-92 that the game was introduced. The rules were made out and hung in the
                "gym" for the inspection of players before the game was ever tried. The men were a little skeptical at
                first about it, but after the ball was once thrown up no coaxing was needed to induce them to play.
                Basket ball came into general favor first through the Y.M.C.A. Having been introduced through the
                association it was natural that it should spread through that medium. Before long, however, colleges
                began to investigate and adopt the game, and in the short space of seven years it has gained a wide
                popularity. In the Eastern colleges, both for men and for women, basket ball is the reigning favorite
                among sports. The rules are not changed for the young women players, though doubtless the game is
                played with a bit more tenderness.

                Though at first sight the game appears to be a free for all scramble, it soon becomes evident that a
                number of scientific plays are possible. Unfailing good judgment and good muscular control are the
                first requisites for a good player. The treatment of the ball is the subject of several rules.
                It can be tossed, rolled on the floor and pushed around, but must never be kicked. There are no
                signals, and a play lasts until the ball is passed into the basket.

                Teams in the University

                The Kansas university men are going to be great basket ball enthusiasts. Each class has a picked
                team, and places on the teams are as much sought as on the varsity eleven. Among faculty members
                there are two teams - the Snow hall and the Frazer hall, representing the scientists and the literary
                men. On the former team Dr. Williston, Marshall Barber, Clarence McClung, A.H. Clark and Dr. Naismith
                hold positions. Their opponents are A.G. Canfield, W.H. Carruth, E.M. Hopkins, M.W. Sterling and Archie
                Hogg. On Tuesdays and Thursdays at 3 p.m. these distinguished individuals lay aside their dignity and
                their collars, don sweaters and pugilistic airs, and come forth into the arena to do battle.
                With a grace that is acquired only through long years of bending over desks and laboratory tables,
                they scamper now here, now there, after the elusive canvas sphere.

                When the faculty teams met for their last practice, Chancellor Snow appeared. He was immediately
                besieged to play. The chancellor protested that he was too green, but such fetching invitations could
                never be turned down. The head of the university disappeared into a dressing room, and in a few moments,
                he emerged in a costume of which the most noticeable features were white canvas shoes, a seraphic grin,
                and a neutral tinted sweater. With characteristic vigor he attacked the game, and before long he was the
                champion player. There is nothing slow about the chancellor when he gets into action.

                Tournament in January

                On January 13 an indoor tournament will be given. Basket ball will be the chief feature of the
                exhibition. The old skating rink on Kentucky street will probably be rented for the occasion.
                Dr. Naismith says he enjoys working with college men far better than with others. He believes there is
                no artificiality whatever about college students. "If a man is a man they will respect him and his
                endeavors in their behalf," he says, "but they won't stand trifling a minute. When I find a young fellow
                who kicks on the referee's decisions, I just ask him to call fouls for a few moments. After he has
                called a few and other men have kicked on his rulings, he never kicks again."

                Dr. Naismith has much influence over the young men in his charge. In Mrs. Cora McCollum Smith he has
                an able colleague. The revolution in feeling which a few years have brought about among the physical
                culture students is remarkable. When the training was first introduced about four years ago and the
                girls first donned their suits, the presence of a man within a radius of three blocks wrought the most
                awful consternation. Now men pass back and forth through the gym to and from the laboratory during the
                girls' classes and nothing is thought of it. Before long the girls will try basket ball, too. Equal
                suffrage in athletics is one of the charms of Kansas university. Visitors to Lawrence must get a basket
                ball guide beforehand and learn the lingo, if they wish to be able to converse intelligently with
                university people, for that is the all absorbing topic of the day.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1907-02-24/ed-1/?sp=30&amp;q=College+Athletes+William+Lush+Basket+Base+Ball+Sport+Game+Basketball</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>WITH COLLEGE ATHLETES
                Doinei ia tha Field of 8port in Eatt tod
                Watt.
                SITUATION IN THE MIDDLE WEST
                Vbal William Lak, Tale Baa Ball
                Coach, Thinks f Basket Bail
                Flea far Kacalaa; later-eolleg-latc
                "port.
                CoIIprs banket ball being a Sme that
                tin coma to atay. It la only tha part of
                araclouaneaa to take tba pm at tba valu
                ation that baa been put upon It bjr moat
                tollps rnen and admit that tbera ara rea
                son for Ita popularity. Only a while ago
                It was very much the fashion to sneer at
                the same and say thnt it was a girl s
                game and tha like. A short view of a fast
                fame of basket ball Is enough to convlnoe
                anyone that, whatever else it may be, it
                Is not a girl s game when college men
                ylay It.
                The aonr.twhat tardy recognition of the
                endurance and speed giving qualities of
                the game by college coaches now la be
                ginning to arrive. Man who looked at the
                game once with fear because It w.n lm
                jf adding another to what they cmlclred
                too large a list of aporta now ara this
                to sea that It has its place In the winter
                eaaon for helping to develop men for
                the spring outdoor cimpaVn In many
                porta.
                Billy Lnsh mm Basket Ball.
                For a general all round eulogy of the
                game It would be linrJe to find anything
                more complete than tho utterances of
                William Iiush, the former Cleveland baae
                ball player, who la In charge cf the base
                ball team at Tale. It covers the subject
                ao well that It la worth wnile quoting at
                length. Bomeone waa talking to Luah out
                In Bt. Paul when 'he Title basket ball
                team waa there awhile fro nnd thla Is what
                the baae ball coach bad to aay about basket
                ball:
                "Of the various bransnes of college sport
                that go to fill up tbe interim between rhe
                foot ball and baae aall naaaom all have
                gradually given way before basket ball
                until It now atanda as the most popular
                winter sport among the colleges aa well
                as the most useful and benoflclal, both for
                men who are training for one of tha major
                sports and for those whose sole r art ..In
                college athletics la plav.d on the gym
                nasium floor In thla branch.
                "For ten yeara or more It haa been
                growing gradually in college favor and
                even without the forward pasa of the foot
                ball field to throw it Into still brighter
                relief the game was sure to win Its way
                on the merits of Its play. The qualities It
                demands and those It develops were enough
                In themselves to Insure ultimata favor, but
                the play of the last few yeara in the Inter
                collegiate banket ball league, together with
                the audden prominence which the grafting
                of ita forward pass on the fot ball tulea
                has given It, placea basket ball far ahead
                of the position It held In former yenra
                and gives an added Importance to the play
                of thla aeason, both Inside and outside the
                league.
                What It Develops.
                "Among tha qualities developed In the
                men who take It up seriously are coolness,
                decision, auppleneas, activity and team
                play. Weight, height and auperlor strength
                are advantageous, but with the exception
                of the center position, where height Is a
                requisite, there is no special premium put
                upon any of theae qualities. Speed and
                agility are the qualities most desirable.
                After them come endurance and the ability
                to submerge self In order to play for and
                with the team. The new man at the game
                Is apt to be 'all nerves.' He passes too
                quickly, worka too hard, and when he gets
                a chance to shoot for a goal he Invariably
                doea It too quickly, with tbe result that his
                try misses, where an Instant's hesitation
                for poise and aim would have converted
                bis worthless try Into a valuable goal.
                "It Is disconcerting to know that one
                man on the other team Is specially placed
                to guard' him and the knowledge that he
                Is ever near and trying his utmost to In
                tercept the shot gives a green man the
                rattles' as quickly as anything could.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042242/1910-03-06/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Basket+Ball+Basketball+Intuition+Asset+Game+Sport+Baskets</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>By JAMES NAISMITH
                Basket-ball Intuition—the art of
                knowing just where to be and what
                to do when you get there under cer
                tain conditions during the progress1
                of a game—is a quality which devotees
                of the sport acquire only after several
                years' participation. In football and
                baseball events move along with sys
                tematic regularity, but in this indoor
                game the unexpected is happening
                every minute. One instant the ball
                may be in the possession of your op
                ponents in the vicinity of their goal—
                then every muscle is strained with
                only defense in view—but a second
                later one of your players may have
                secured tbe sphere and at that instant
                your whole theme is to get away from
                your individual opponent in order to
                open up an avenue through which tbe
                ball may be passed to you without al
                lowing an opportunity to block the
                pass.
                The ball may be located in a bunch
                of wriggling players, each endeavoring,
                without violating the rules, to get
                it away from its possessor. A score of
                conditions can prevail in just this In
                stance, and they may be dispelled or
                multiplied in far less time than it
                takes to relate it. If in such a scrim
                mage one of your men holds the ball
                in his hands it is your duty to either
                take the pass from him if he can dis
                entangle himself or locate yourself
                in the vicinity of the basket in order
                that you may receive a pass from him
                or from another of your players.
                Perhaps in that instance you can
                aid by blocking an opponent coming
                down the floor to help perhaps you
                can grab it from your comrade by a
                rush past him perhaps you can do
                more good by being ready to receive
                a throw beneath the goal perhaps—
                but what's the use.
                Every detail, combined with dozens
                of other details, goes to make up a
                condition for which your movements
                must be suited. A dozen games or
                more and these requirements begin to
                dawn upon the player who is a com
                parative novice. Advice helps in
                giving a theory to fellow out, but, as
                my friend Prof. Lewis Gillesby at
                Northwestern university once said:
                "The only way to become successful
                in all lines of the sport Is simply a
                blamed hard grind three nights a
                week in practice."
                So in presenting the plays which are
                illustrated in the diagram in this ar
                ticle, I am branding them "Intuition
                Plays." Take the one In the diagram
                to the left. This illustrates a condi
                tion during which your opponents are
                endeavoring to make a free toss from
                the foul line, after one of the players
                of the team represented as aggressor
                has violated tbe rules.
                INTUITION IS AN ASSET IN BASKETBALL
                No. 6 is an opponent trying for a
                goal from fouul. He throws the ball
                in the direction of his basket, op
                ponents and aggressors being lined up
                along the fouled lines. The center (No.
                3) of tbe aggressors, being supposedly
                the tallest man and best Jumper of his
                quintet, gets the ball as It caroms off
                the goal in case of a possible failure
                by No.
                In the meantime, the guard (No. 4)
                and a forward (No. 2) have separated
                themselves from the jam around the
                basket, the former taking up a position
                near the center of the floor while the
                latter moves to a point just to the
                right and a little up *:he floor.
                Then the center heaves the ball to
                No. 2, who in turn sails It toward his
                own goal, where it Is met by No. 4 on
                the run. Thence into the basket.
                The positions of NOB. 2 and 3 may
                be filled by any of the players, but for
                ward and center are perhaps best. The
                reason, as I see it, Is because the cen
                ter Is generally the best fitted physic
                ally to leap into the air and corral
                the sphere because of the height and
                jumping qualifications which are the
                center's essentials. Then in the case
                of No. 2, a forward under the goal of
                I his opponents has no one to guard
                from a throw at the basket, for usually
                his guard will lay back in the vicinity
                of the center.
                In No. 4's case, It is the old order of
                things In which a forward seldom fol
                lows his guard opponent, and conse
                quently the latter should be free for
                an easy throw at the net. Your team
                may Bwltch off in order to bewilder
                opponents by changing men for cer
                tain duties In that play, for it is a
                known fact among basket ball coach
                es that Just about three goals wrung
                from opponents by that combination
                will make the latter wary and each
                man will stick so closely to his In
                dividual opponent that perhaps further
                nttenuts will be frustrated. So. It la
                best to have several signals for this
                play, using it first with a combination
                of players on one side of the goal and
                then on the other side. After that a
                change of the combination of men by
                prearranged signals is for tbe best. If
                that is fathomed also, allow several
                attempts at baskets from the foul line
                to pass without the play then spring
                it again.
                In the diagram to the light I am
                giving a play to be used when the ball
                Is out of bounds and in the hands of
                tbe team represented as aggressor.
                This illustrates only one condition, but
                it points out the theory for use when
                the sphere is out of play at other
                points of tbe floor area.
                We will suppose that the guard (No.
                4) Is in possession of the sphere out
                of bounds and under tbe opponents'
                goal, for then the situation is fraught
                with real danger to your tally sheets.
                Guard No. 4 makes a cross-floor pass
                to his teammate guard (No. 5),
                who in turn shoots the sphere
                to his own center (No. 3) by
                meanB of another cross-fire throw, the
                center being in the vicinity of the
                middle of the floor. One of the for
                wards (in this instance No. 1) crosses
                In front of the basket so as to "lose"
                bis opposing guard and takes the pass
                from the center on the right-hand side
                of the goal, from which point be
                makes his effort to score.
                This combination Is evolved on the
                time-honored principle that a cross
                the-floor pass should always follow a
                throw straight down the playing area
                —only here we go a step farther by
                eliminating the throw straight down
                the floor.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1903-09-20/ed-1/?sp=24&amp;q=High+School+Girls+Illustrating+Play+Basket+Ball</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>HIGH SCHOOL GIRLS ILLUSTRATING PLAY AT BASKETBALL</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1907-02-10/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Fouls+Basket+Ball+Basketball+Rules+Dribble</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>TOO MANY FOULS IN BASKETBALL
                Present Rules Too TooPrevent Stric StrjcPrevent E
                Prevent Much M uch SpectacnX SpectacnXlar pectacu Nev
                lar larPlaying larPlayingBY Playing PlayingBY 2 2l 2BY
                l
                BY ELWOOD S
                BROWN tcz tczThere e eThere l lThQre18
                There ThQre18 to A growing f irJ r rthe y ytho th ththo
                tho middle weat for 4it hhr br a chs ch
                the A A U b bII bsiktbah k ketball tbaN d ia ort or oriberal I
                liberal l interpretation interJ1 tation of ofg Mim 7 Ths
                irtg h j g hRs grown rown up U berus be beea lIst ot f fhat tht l lthnt t ttlmt
                hat t the present pr 8ent rules are t t1O tmittlag uW Ui Uimlttfug jlse jlsemlttlng
                mlttlng prHgUc pra prctlcslly tlctLU Uly no mom for forspectacular futS1 futS1spectacular fu fuspectnoulflr
                spectacular plays pla s Fouls Fouksuch It ro cared I Isuch
                such trivial offences ani an anhat fr frtlmt AXE AXEthat
                that t many man games ar are areeating n Ilw and andosting tIIDt
                eating because of thl thI8H thimunicated fn i j ht Z gin ginmunicated
                municated with promine prominerom premium q isket ket j f ffrom a aIrom
                from f rom Chicago west Mila iiiialmost na c ctlmost foj fojalmost
                almost a unanimous unnnimo B desIre f a T Tthat
                that t will eliminate th the i pr ierail1zr r ni OTt2SSa OTt2SSacalling t
                c amn fouls Fouls minl 8J1tet K5 K5l r
                calling are b bt ll1lnC inin inina 1000tbl
                il a l IClVtWl CReror facIor lit In UlllJWOb almost OWIY every everyLooking iiIP J nI ir
                Looking over the recent rpCt recentn nt J tnuj m
                In i n and around Chicago li 4 i AHW AHWby Afd
                thc t he Chicago Centnll Y M 1 l A
                that t to per cent Of them tr tre trey
                by b y free frt throws thr ws In a Ram am with withumble Jtb au n
                lumbla h University 01 fouls Wre v re tee
                the t he time consumed In walk Wftlklg g ft ftbringing f fj5 fj5asket
                bnsket b to another trying t tringing thro1
                r
                bringing b the ball back to nter tt ter ternintites r i 111 z zminutes
                minutes i cutting the actual jw1n ayintn u
                down to 9 minutes In a i gmEo gmEothe
                the t he Crescent Five team wl wllast w wist l va valast s
                last l st week and the Jvansan snsas tity 11 tv j jclub A 1 1club
                club c lub 67 fouls were called cutting cuttg9ir cuttg9irowi in inprevious Hr
                down d owi eten more materially than thanrevious tL
                previous p Instance This sort of ofourse ti ticourse thq UI UIcourse
                course c has a stagnating effect f fenUre
                etEd ujxi np
                entire e game gme monopolizes monopolzes most f tth tthauses UJ tb tbcauses tl W Wcauses
                causes c the players to relax ari arl 3 I Io i iginger
                cs
                ginger s and In i inn
                general Generl makes the thean ui uin
                an a n exhibition of clever free freerather tl thrw thrwtacular t
                rather than good team work l lluther
                luther tem a aacular
                tacular t field Celd baskets basketsPlayers bukets an 11 43 3
                Players in East to Blame Blame j9J P Pblame og ogOf
                I Iblame
                or course the plaer players U are Te In j p 1
                blame for fot this because bacus th twy y foul p
                fou
                opponents opponent much more than is nee
                Very Y ry little Utta objection objecton is made Iadt when Jec htr
                are called caled for holding tripping A
                tackle t running runnln the with the thf th trpping ball LH h hoffenses and anding 8 8offcnses
                fnc
                offenses but tepresnt preSfnt ytm o t
                ing i ng a foul on someone somenp Eo V er TV tini tinimen tn
                men i touch each other evry fr tltneTj Hme tln
                moves an Inch and Vnn l
                every timf time timearm 1m 1marm m marm
                arm arm gets part way around an uppcEeni I
                dead ded wrong and Is spoiling spiing th UPJt gas ga b
                gl
                loge lee rules rule permit permi a great deal more f
                teal moe
                dom of play pIn than do the A A f TL TLto i aD
                The college dribble rule
                colege permitting a
                to throw the ball In the th pritn air or roll k i I t tthe
                the floor take ta1t any number numbfr of steps stei rol t
                catch it and try for or a baskft bkft i i is isone steP M I f JM1 JM1one
                one The A A I r rules rul s make it a I dl
                for a man to take more than two tw i vl t i
                in a dribble In regard resrd t to the therule pror
                rule rle a man running at full ful speed p us r rnecessarily l lnecessariy
                necessarily necessariy take an extra step spe or orand uj i1 r rand
                and his momentum usually usual bring brjn brjnar bringsarm jjr
                arm ar in contact contct with wih his opponent L P Pspite
                spite of the fact fac that tht the opponet rules rule saylL sy say
                lowance Jownce shall shal be made md for a man mancatches r rcatches
                catches the ball while whie on the run ru runare f fare Etj Etjcatches e eare
                are invariably called caUe If a man eve evemuch t evemuch r
                much as takes a small smal extra step stepCauses 1 1much t t tt tCauses
                Causes Many Fouls FoulsAnother fra fraAnother
                Ie IeAnother</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1915-12-26/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Basket-Ball+Basketball+Basket+Ball+Game+Sport</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>BASKETBALL HAS MADE GREAT PROGRESS IN THE LAST 25 YEARS
                Dy JACK HAAS.
                The game of basketball originated
                oer twenty-five ears ago. It was
                Invented to satisfy the need of team
                competition under indoor conditions In
                which large numbers of relatively
                untrained people could take part. The
                majority of games that were being
                piajed prior to basketball failed to
                achieve any great Influence, nor did
                they gain any wide popularity
                All of our standard games are the
                result of a gradual evolution and
                have developed because they possess
                ed those qualities that appeal strongly
                to play or the fighting spirit. The
                demands for special skill, speed and
                strategy that is required in those who
                indulge in baseball and football, are
                great factors in the real pleasure and
                interest that accompany the playing
                or watching of these games, and are
                in a large measure responsible for
                their development and wide popular
                ity. "Until the invention of basket-ball
                there was no Indoor game that was
                in any way comparable to baseball
                and football In these respects. The
                need for an Indoor game that could
                be used by active, sturdy men was
                keenly realized by the faculty of the
                Y. M. C. A. Training School at Spring
                field, Mass. Dr. James A. Naismlth.
                now a member of the Collegiate Basket-ball
                Committee, was an Instructor
                at this school In 1S91 and undertook
                to devise an Indoor game which
                should satisfy these general specifica
                tions. Basketball In Its first form was very
                simple in Its plan and technique. It
                was designed to be plajed by as
                many as could occupy the playing
                space, nine to fifty plaers on each
                side.
                It soon became apparent that too
                many plavers In a gams hindered the
                development of team work; so after
                a time the number of players on a
                team was reduced to nine. A little
                later, about 1S94, the number of play
                ers on the teams was determined by
                the area of the floor on which the
                game was played.
                For the first year or two, at the
                start of the game, the men were lined
                up at the opposite ends of the field
                and rushed for the ball when it was
                tossed by the official Into the middle
                of the playing space. This was modi
                fled in 1S94 so that the ball was toss
                ed up in the middle of the field and
                had to be touched, by the center men,
                to make the play legal.
                In the meantime. In 1891-91, the
                good qualities of the game were rec
                ognized by Miss Berenson, the direc
                tor of physical training at Smith Col
                lege, and she Introduced It as a part
                of the gymnasium work for girls. In
                order to lessen the physical strain,
                which was found to be too severe for
                girls playing the men's rules, the
                floor was divided Into three sections
                by lines running across the Held at
                right angles to the side lines. The
                centers (the girls' teams under these
                rules, which are essentially unchanged
                today, haye two centers), the two
                guards, and the two forwards, are re
                stricted to their own sections of the
                floor, so that the players in a given
                section have an opportunity to get a
                breathing spell when the ball Is in
                any other part of the field. This de
                vice not only made the game less
                strenuous but also favored the de
                velopment of team play.
                It U doubtful If the history af coat-
                jt-JVV A,-evi.-
                petitlve games contains an example of
                more rapid growth than that shown
                by basket-ball during the first two
                or three years of Its existence. Even
                ...im. nwwic pjnrau ji iM?cuail ill
                the jears immediately following the
                civil war was second to this. The
                rapidity with which the knowledge of
                basket-ball spread throughout the
                world was due. first to the fact that
                the game was so constituted that it
                met in an adequate way the real need
                for a vigorous Indoor game, and, sec
                ond, the game was developed In an
                institution which sent Us students, all
                of whom had learned to pla) the
                game, to all parts of the world.
                The movement which has resulted In
                the formal co-operation of the rules
                committees representing the Young
                Men's Christian Association, the Ama
                teur Athletic Union, and the National
                Collegiate Association, promises to be
                a most valuable Influence In promot
                ing the development of the game of
                basket-ball along right lines and
                should mark the beginning of a new
                epoch in the history of the game as a
                most desirable and useful indoor
                sport.
                Basket-ball makes no uncertain de
                mands on heart and lungs and on en
                durance generally. It develops alert
                ness, self-control, skill, i-peed and
                team work; and It brings Into action
                every part of the body. A good game
                of basket-ball arouses Interest and
                enthusiasm In both player and specta
                tor. Its essential simplicity and the
                small amount of inexpensive apparatus
                required, taken In connection with Its
                other qualifications, make it one of
                the most valuable of our competitive
                games.
            </text>
        </result>
        <!-- Custom search query -->
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/sports-industry/basketball</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>
                Basketball
                Color photograph of professional basketball court from the darkened stands
                Carol M. Highsmith, photographer. Chicago Bulls basketball game at the United Center, Chicago, Illinois. Carol M. Highsmith Archive. Library of Congress Prints and Photographs Division.
                The sport of basketball traces its history back to 1891 when James Naismith, a physical education professor and instructor trying to keep his gym class active wanted a indoor game to keep his students occupied and maintain the proper levels of fitness even during winters. Eventually, he wrote a few basic rules and nailed a peach basket onto a 10-foot elevated track and basketball was born.

                The sport has grown since those early days when it was predominantly associated with colleges and high schools. When the National Basketball Association (NBA) was founded, there were 17 teams, but by 2018 that more than doubled to 38: there was a professional women's league, many universities had both women's and men's teams, and it had become a big international sport.

                Men's Basketball
                The National Basketball Association (NBA) is the league that represents professional men's basketball. It traces its history to two leagues - the National Basketball League (NBL) founded in 1937 and the Basketball Association of America (BAA) founded in 1946 - that merged in 1949.

                Interest in major league basketball games originally was predominantly about people going to the game, but the attention to games has gone beyond that. In the 1950's games began to be televised when the league signed a contract with DuMont, and in the early 1960's they signed a deal with NBC and other big networks which meant an even bigger audience. The advent of cable brought additional opportunities including deals with USA Networks and ESPN. Television and cable expanded basketball's viewership and, consequently, interest in the game in the U.S. and internationally. The 21st century has brought in fans following games on Twitter and Facebook, giving the league and teams the additional benefit of connecting to fans around the world.

                As with other big team sports, revenue and expenses at the professional level are tied to television contracts, player salaries, attendance figures, and licensing fees and arena revenues. Player, owner, and league relations are often dictated by the collective bargaining agreement because of revenue-sharing formulas and salary caps.

                Regular games and post season play expand viewership and revenues but the NBA like other sports associations, has instituted additional revenue and interest opportunities. The All-Star game has become the All-Star Weekend with the addition of specific events/contests like the Rising Stars Challenge, the Slam Dunk Contest, the Three-Point Contest, and Skills Challenge. Even the G League participates with the G League Dream Factory Friday Night and the G League All-Star Game. The NBA has also sponsored Summer League which is an off-season competition and features rookie, sophomore and G League affiliate players.

                Basketball has grown as an international sport, particularly connected to the Olympics and the NBA has also made a push into markets like China External, Europe, and Mexico. Beyond that, in December 2018 it was announced that the Indiana Pacers and Sacramento Kings would play two preseason games in Mumbai in October 2019.External

                Here in the U.S. there have been major changes in recent history that have increased the interest in basketball: the introduction of a women's professional basketball league and, even more recently, an official minor NBA league.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/sports-industry/general-internet</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/sports-industry/managing-venues/venue-managing-naming</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-jim-thorpe/introduction</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Considered the best all-around athlete of modern times, Native American James "Jim" Thorpe won gold
                medals in both the pentathlon and the decathlon in the 1912 Stockholm Summer Olympics. Scandal struck
                in late January 1913 when he was stripped of his titles by the Amateur Athletic Union after admitting
                he had played professional baseball prior to the Games. Within days of the judgement, however, Thorpe
                had signed on with the New York Giants and went on to play years of professional baseball, football,
                and basketball. </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/sports-industry/baseball</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MANY KILLED IN EXPLOSION</text>
          Escaping Gas in Boston Subway
          Works Great Havoc.
          HALF A HUNDRED INJURED
          PnsHlng Electric Cnr "Wrecked and
          Adjoining Ituildiiigg Itadly Dam
          aged Partial Liht of Dead and
          Disabled Accident Occurred ut
          Tremont and Boylston Streets.
          Boston, March 4. An explosion lias just
          occurred in the subway excavation at the
          corner of Trcraont and Ooylston streets.
          Three electric cars that were passing
          at the time were wrecked and one ot
          them was burned. Several bulldingsin the
          vicinity were more or less damaged.
          The explosion was caused by escaping
          gas.
          Among the buildings damaged are the
          Hotel Pclliam, the Knickerbocker and
          Head buildings and the Masonic Temple.
          Window glass in buildings within 200
          feet of the scene of the explosion were
          shattered.
          At least twelve persons were killed.
          Four bodies have been removed to un
          dertaking' rooms.
          Forty-two persons arc at the Emergency
          Hospital.
          Among the dead are:
          Rev. W. A. Slack, professor at Tufts Col
          lege. G. I). Bigclow, conductor.
          Unknown man and woman.
          The injured include James Reardon, John
          J. O'Conuor, Thomas F. Ford, Mrs. J. R.
          Wilson, Nellie Jackson, Lucy Dolan, F.
          W. Tceling, and Mrs. F. A. reck
          There seems to be no doubt thatatleast
          eight persons were immediately killed.
          The explosion came Jutt as the streetcars
          were almost in the ceutcr of the space at
          the corner.
          The first car was In the center when the
          explosion came. The whole of the wood
          work, which is used as a bridge over the
          subway, was lifted into the air, carrying
          the first car with it and taking along the
          two horses of the second car. The other
          Tehlcles were lifted straight into the air,
          but came down on the tracks. Instantly
          the air was filled with flying debris.
          The firat electric car, the one in which
          most or the killed were riding, no sooner
          reached the track than It broke in hair,
          and the whole portion Immediately burst
          into flame. Then someone sounded a fire
          alarm. This brought a large rescue force
          to the scene, and almost immediately calls
          were being sent out hurriedly for the am
          bulances. It was an awful Eight that met the gaze
          of those who were first on the scene. In
          the center was the long blazing electric
          car. .Close beride this were the bodies ot
          the two horses killed instantly, and about
          ten, twenty, thirty feet away from where
          the woodwork of the car was blazing lay
          the dead and wounded people. Those who
          wore not injured in the cars on Boylston
          6treet were Incapable ot action
          at first, and people in the buildings and
          stores surrounding did not know what had
          occurred, but it did not take them long
          to secure their senses, and almost imme
          diately there was a rush to the assistance
          ot the wounded.
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-05-08/ed-1/?sp=57&amp;q=New+subway+York</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=NEW+OPENED+SUBWAY+YORK</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+BOSTONS+SUBWAY+subway</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COMPLETED AND IN OPERATION.
                A BRI0I1TI.T UOIITED Tl NNW. AFKfU'.PlN?: RAPID
                TRANSIT FOR BLECTRIO CARS CONORS
                TIO? OV TUB BTREET9 RELIEVBD,
                The subway for streetcars In Boston, a pari
                of whli h has Ju il b >a op? n? -i for at rvlce. is an
                em.???? of more than local Interest The ne
                eesslty for some relief t? the i rowded thorough?
                fares above it can besl be appre? lat? d, of course,
                by H lonlans; but tl?.- Modem Aib.n.s is i?; no
                means th.ily cltj In this countr) which is
                beset with problems of the same character.
                ThofO who :ii" familiar v.iih "!h- lay of tiie
                land" in Bosl? n remember thai Tremont-st. runs
                In a ajenerall) north-and-aonth direction and
                forms ihe istern boundary of th.- Common.
                Ii i-; intersected by Rovlston-st., which consti?
                tutes Ihe southern boundary of thai historic
                parle On the Boylsl m and Tremonl st edges
                of the Common there is a broad promenade.
                known as the Mall. The main part of the sub?
                ira. li. h Is w Id nough to a? commodate four
                tracks, passes under ihe Tremonl st. Mall, and.
                niter passing under Park-st, which lies along
                the northern side if ine Common, extends mr
                will extend, when completed) to Scollay ?Square,
                thence eastward to Adams Square, ami finally
                up northward again to Hayraarkel Square.
                This terminus Is close to the great union rail?
                way station .it the North End.
                Ft en th.- oin, r of Tri mont and Boylston sts.
                there are two extensions, wldn enough f>?r only
                a double track. Boylston st. Mall for about '.k"> feet, and then
                ascends an Incline through an op? n ul for ,'il*
                feel The terminal station for this branch la
                situated In th- Public Gardens. The other
                branch reaches away to the southward, and. on
                nearlng th- Junction of Bhawmul ave. and Tn
                mont-st., forks. A separate two-track incline
                leads up into each of those streeta
                Including th? Inclines, ihe subway has a total
                length of about a mile and a half, und will con?
                tain about five miles of track Al present the
                branches from th.rn.-r of Boylston and Tre?
                monl Bl.-. and th-- main line up to Park-Si. an
                In operation. A great >l-.il o? work has already
                been done on the northern portion of the route,
                arid it is h? i I thai everything all) be finished
                within th> n \t eight months. Hi und wats
                broken for the subway in April, 1805, twenty
                Bine month- ago.
                The depth of this underground passageway Is
                1 I f. t. The Width IS L'i feel for I WO T.|. l(S, .11,d
                18 feel f.-r f? ur. Al Int rvala of sis r- et, along the
                side.-, si--. I posts are b t up on at.1 foundatl >nB,
                and from the tops of those on one side there
                r? rn h a? n i to the top ..f o, i th? r
                stul roof beams. Where there arc four tracks
                there is a c? ntral lia.f posts in the turn I, In
                addition to those along the sides, From one
                ro i am t.? the n sl th? re cxl nd an ai h of
                ma t.ry. These su Iv? ai hi f. mil I hi
                roof, an covered with coni-rete; ind th?
                mat? lal HI th? pace betWi'.-i
                the Bides. A waterproof I
                i In es iding from I .....a, wat r that
                                                  other? leak n fi ml ill. Th? m i
                ?onry floor is d, like an Inv? rted ar. h,
                an l al ng II ?rural line iher? r in i a dra n At
                Int? r\ ala the train a pit, from
                which, whem ver the wat? r rises to a
                level, the contents arc withdrawn bj auti i il
                ally con troll? I 1?. :r,,- pumps
                V? ntllatlon Is ff? '.-l by hui i ?l irj ran
                establish? d in masonrj it thi or four
                pointa along the i ne. The air Is suck l out of
                the subway, and forced upward thi ugh the
                op nfnga to Ihe level of ihe ?trei-i, ll u dr I of
                                                               Im and? m i ctrlc imi and scores of an
                Hghta ai i advanl ig? i al ?ng Ihe in
                terl? r. As clectrlelt) i>d for th?
                propulsion of the i ara hi? h i il
                th? r.- la i. smoke lo a? umulat? i n the -Mings,
                and no foul gases to offend the fa i rv?i
                Tin-re is no reason why th? pla h ..-1 n I r?
                main lean, sweet and bright for years.
                AI th? und? rground r irse, the
                subway is broaden? I A high Air? fenc? runa
                lengthwise In the middle, irallng the two
                noi thboui -1 tr u from the tw?i soul hi un I.
                The tra- lu of e.i., t, p.ur are Ivided i rial n
                gineers call an "island platform." saj feel
                wide, and 300 or IfSJ feel long. Ace? i.m tie
                had to on? platform from the ??(her onlj b) pro
                Ing down a low flight of ita ai i through a
                narrow bul brightly Illuminated pas age undei
                n- ath, oi i going up i the street and rosslng
                iv? r.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Boston+subway</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Riding Astride Makes Little
                Headway Among Ladies
                There Is a rumor that the bean-cat-,
                Ing, blue-blooded Boston dames have
                mounted a new bobby. They rldo
                astride. Not the bobby, but the horse.
                They think this Is a good time to be
                gin, says the New York Sun. Since
                the Boston subway uus completed, a
                large part of the population spends Its
                time underground, riding back and
                forth through the tunnel and exclaim
                ing: "Wo did It!
                This has Increased the above-ground
                Inhabitants to so small a number that
                It's a good time to oercomo public
                opinion, because there's so little of It
                to overcome. Consequently thd Boston
                women refeired to t:nn seized the
                chance to establish the new fad In rid
                ing. They Know that by the tlmo the
                people get tired ut looking nt their hole
                In the ground, bloomers will nave be
                come a pait of thfl Boston eieed of B's.
                Its growing. Already It Includes Bos
                ton bens, Boston bays, Boston blue
                blood and Boston has bleus,
                Within a few wck the same rumor
                has broken out nearer home. Newspa
                per paragraphs have declared that New
                York women, too, are going to aban
                don the side puddle, aud takn to di
                vided skirts. Doctors uho have been
                consulted sigh and Bay they only wish
                tuc rumor would come true. They do
                what they tan to push It along. They
                prescribe tiding nstilde, and say It Is.
                tho only healthful and safe way for
                anybody to tide. But tbij tity that
                It'R ono of the presctltplons which New
                iork women u.iu o tar declined to
                take.
                And yet theto Is a pcislstent rumor
                In tho all' that women huvo been seen
                riding nstilde ocn In tho paik. Tho
                regular pom emeu have it certain repu-1
                tatlnn for blindness, but there ts no
                particular reason why it paik polite-!
                mnn fahuuld have trouble with his ryes.
                nil uujii iu Hiinw u mciu are any
                visions cf namzons In. dUlilcd skirts
                flitting nlonj; tho bridle paths there
                cummer daja. Several polltemea were, I
                tlteiefure, approached on tho subject.
                "Ilev I seen anny vtiamcn rliiln' I
                nulliridc lately? said one. "No I nin't.
                They was t,u thiec actresses done It
                a few yea is ago, but I ain't never seen
                no lady u-doln" It."
                At the riding academies the rumor
                fared quite, as badly.
                "No,1' said ono of the German tiding
                masters, "ve aind god no ladles rtdln'
                asdrlde In our agademy."
                "Say, you ride better than you talk,"
                put In another one. "Sits his English
                sort of sideways, doesn't ho?" us the
                German went off. "No, there's not a
                single lady, nor a married one either,
                riding astride In our academy. And I
                don't think you'll And one In any of
                tbo cither academies. They don't want
                to hero in New York."
                "Do they rldo that way In tho coun
                try?" "I don't know. We had ono woman
                who wanted to lenrn to ride astride,
                She took a few lessons, but never went
                nny farther than that."
                "They rldo nstrldo In England. Do
                you think that If It becomes tho uni
                versal stylo over thoro New York
                women will follow It?"</text>
        </result>

        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-06-07/ed-1/?sp=30&amp;q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>
                BOSTON'S SUBWAY, SURFACE AND ELEVATED LINES
                PRACTICALLY TIED UP BY STRIKE
                Boston, June 7. By noon to
                day the surface, elevated and sub
                way car system of Boston and
                suburbs was utterly disorganized.
                A strike of the union employes
                of the Boston Elevated, which
                controls the surface and subway
                lines, was called at 4:15 o'clock
                this morning after a stormy three
                hour session at union headquar
                ters. The elevated officials laughed
                at the strike. When the union was
                formed only a few weeks ago the
                elevated set about a counter or
                ganization, a "protective" asso
                ciation they called it.
                This morning the officials of
                the company claimed they had
                2,000 men in this protective asso
                ciation who would continue to
                work, and that they had 1,500
                strike-breakers already imported
                from New York and Philadelphia.
                There was a good deal of riot
                ing after the strike was called.
                Cars wer.e stoned, trolleys discon
                nected, motormen and conductors
                who refused to recognize the
                strike order roughly handled,
                le,epers were put on the tracks,
                and cautious Bostonians walked
                to work this morning.
                But the rioting never became
                very serious and it was not neces
                sary. As the forenoon wore on
                motormen after motormen, and
                conductor after conductor left
                their 'packed cars standing'in the
                street and went to union head
                quarters to report.
                Even wherfe they did not leave
                the cars there always was some
                one to disconnect the trolley
                wires. Then the motormen and
                conductors would refuse to get
                off to fix it, and the police would
                have to do it.
                Because the guards at the
                Park street terminal of the Cam-
                bridge subway reported to the
                union the escalators were stopped
                and passengers had to climb three
                flights of stairs to the street.
                There are 3,800 members of the
                union. The strike was called be
                cause
                The company refused to recog
                nize the union; announced it
                would employ no union .men.
                When complaints were made
                against men, they were laid off
                without pay pending a hearing.
                If exonerated and reinstated,
                the pay they lost never was made
                up. i
                Conductors were forced to fur
                nish $10 change for each trip.
                Despite the company's refusal
                of an increase because their
                "finances wquld not stand it,"
                the "loyal federation or protec
                tive asspciation" members' pay
                was increased when the union
                was formed.
                Police Commissioner O'Meara
                ordered all the reserves on duty
                at the subway and elevated, sta
                tions and car barns this forenoon.
                There already have been fifty arm
                rests, but all the cases were con
                tinued until oMnday.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87078082/1910-12-07/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Boston+Subway+subway+suicide+SUICIDE</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>JOHN F. D0N0HUE A SUICIDE.
                Thomas
                Lawson's Confidential Man
                Dies In Subway.
                Boston, Dec. 1. John F. Donohue,
                many years the confidential man of J.
                Edward Addicks aud of Thomas W.
                Lawsou, committed suicide by throw-!
                lng himself before a fast moving train
                in the subway. Deatli was install Ui- i
                neous.
                For about fifteen minutes Mr. Dono
                hue had been pacing the station plat
                form, walking to tho edge and looking
                down at the rails and peering up and
                down the track. Just before a north
                bound train drew up Mr. Donohue
                dropped a light cane lie had been car
                rying and jumped into the train pit
                His family furnished no explanation
                for the act. Friends say he had been
                suffering from stomach trouble about
                a year. He was sixty years old and a
                native of Ireland and for a time was
                engaged lu shoe manufacturing In Lynn,
                Mass</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-08-17/ed-1/?sp=63&amp;q=Boston+subway</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/?sp=42&amp;q=BOSTON+subway</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>THE MARCH OF IMPROVEMENT IS FAST OBLITERATING MANY OF BOSTONS MOST FAMOUS OLD LANDMARKS
                OLD STATIC HOUSE, BOSTON.
                To be transformed Into a tunnel station for the subway
                BOSTON IMPROVEMENTS.
                Historic Landmarks and Crooked
                Streets Disappearing.
                Boston, June 20.— Within three years the
                crooks and turnings and devious wanderings of
                Boston's most honored highways and byways
                will be nothing more than a memory of the past,
                and many of her ancient landmarks will be
                wiped out or so altered as to be unrecognizable
                to the oldest inhabitant. Slowly and surely the
                ancient thoroughfares are being widened,
                straightened and bent into the rulerlike lines oC
                i rosscut New- York. Philadelphia and Chicago.
                Boston is undergoing a transformation below
                arid aloft that would cause Benjamin Franklin.
                John Hancock, "Warren and Paul Revere *.o rub
                their eyes and stare in amazement. Million dol
                lar buildings by the dozen, elevated roads, tun
                nels and streetcar lines beneath the streets and
                under the harbor, swamps and mud Hats filled
                for piers and excavated for docks that ac
                ':;iinodate giant steamers these are the things
                they would see.
                Along State-st., beneath the spot where the
                Boston Massacre occurred, and beneath the his
                toric old State House, a tunnel is eating its way
                from under the harbor to Scollay Square to con
                nect with the present subway by means of
                (lights of stairs and elevators, and thence out
                side to the busy world. The old Slat- House
                itself is to be transformed into a tunnel station
                connecting with a subway line also. The re
                modelled building will soon be crowded with
                people hurrying back and forth, intent on busi
                ness, with never a thought of its old associa
                tions. Little do they think, as they hurry past
                where tunnel workmen are digsing seventy feet
                beneath, of what has happened In that quaint
                old edifice.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023296/1906-06-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=bomb+Bomb+Boston+explosions+FIRE+subway</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>FIRE IN SUBWAY.
                Lives Impcrilled in Boslon's
                Underground Railway.
                Terrlflc Exploslona Caused by 8hort
                Clrcultlng of Heavlly Charoea uiec
                trlc vyirea Hundreds of Men and
                Women Thrown Into Panlc Three
                Persons Injured.
                Boston A dull, low ronr, llko tho
                blast of n chnrge of dynnmlte under
                tona of grnnlte, nnd clouda ot black,
                Blckenlng smoko belchlng fortli,
                threw hundreds of men nnd women
                into a panic nnd paralyzed trnfflc ln
                the subwny nt the Boylston street
                statlon at 5.30 o'clock, Wednesday af-
                ternqpn
                No one know the trouble. Elevatcd
                road employes and offlclals were allke
                confused, and fearful of what mlght
                come next, fla tho smoko raphlly fllleil
                tho stntloim at Boylston and Park
                streets, nnd passengers wers rushed
                from tlie cars to the surfacc.
                Tralnmen nnd statlon pollce at
                tempted to call the flrd departmont
                and found tho telephones so charged
                wlth clectrlclty as to be useless.
                Mnny of the women reachlng the
                subway by the Boylston street cars
                were overcomo by the smoko, falnted,
                nnd had to be dragged to the surfnce.
                Several becanio hysterlcal and woro
                controlled wlth much dimculty, the
                danger belng constant of Bomeono
                falllng from tho platforms overcome
                by tho smoko and becomlng electro
                cuted upon the deadly thlrd rall.</text>
        </result>
        <!-- Custom search query -->
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-new-york-city-subway/selected-articles</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-new-york-city-subway/selected-articles</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1918-08-02/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=subWay</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1922-08-28/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-25/ed-1/?sp=31&amp;q=New+York+Subway</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cocaine</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1898-12-11/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addiction</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE COCAINE MONSTER
        THROWING HIS TENTACLES
        AROUND THE NATION
        HOW IT GRIPS ITS VICTIMS
        The Deadly Drug Whose Influence
        Carries Men to Insanity and
        Death Becoming Too Popular
        Value of cocaine leaves imported at the
        port of New York in 1894.114,384; imported
        in 1807, #54.122; indicated value ot imports
        for 18SKS, $75,000.
        In these simple figures are contained the
        elements of a warning sermon that would
        startle all America. We seem to be rapidly
        becoming a nation of cocaine fiends, it the
        number of those addicted to the u.-e ol the
        dreadful drug continues to increase at the
        present rate the importation of what "as
        originally regarded its a blessed alleviator
        of pain will have to be classed with opium
        ami its use prohibited by law, except tor
        medicinal purposes.
        At present the cocaine Bend can pill-chase
        the drug without trouble and the case with
        which it is taken is a fatal recommenda
        tion to those who crave a nerve-dcadener.
        No laborious cooking of pills over a lamp,
        cleaning of implements or troublesome neces
        sity for secrecy, as with the use of opium.
        Cocaine can be taken at any time, with
        scarcely any trouble, anil without a soul
        besides the being aware ot his being
        in the toils.
        At first, that is. It will not be long before
        every intimate friend will observe c change,
        a gradual ami scarcely perceptible change,
        come over the appearance and general con
        duct of the cocaine fiend. II the one who
        yields to the toxic influence of the drug be
        a lawyer, then it will be noticed that Ilia
        language as he pleads a case in court has
        become particularly diffuse, while his argu
        ments are long drawn out and lacking in
        logic. Others will notice this peculiarity
        and wonder. The victim will be in hli'siul
        ignorance of anything wrong, for another
        queer phase of the progress ot cocaine pots-
        Suing is that il lulls the user into a de
        lightful feeling of self-satisfaction, and,
        whatever his shortcomings, he is contented
        ami happy—until the influence of the drug
        departs and leaves him only with the dead
        ly craving for more that none can tight oil.
        The lecturer who becomes a victim to the
        cocaine habit will, to the surprise ot his
        audience, spend the enure period allotted
        to a certain subject on a single insignificant
        part of it, or seem to tot get the topic en
        tirely and wander into something entirely
        foreign. It will strike the listeners that
        the learned lecturer has been drinking or is
        beginning lo get feeble-minded, there will
        be nothing in lie appearance or manner of
        the speaker to indicate that he himself has
        the slightest knowledge that he lias not
        been treating the subject in the brightest
        and most careful way. Cocaine is a drug
        that deludes its victims. It i- the very devil
        blmsell in tin form of an innocent-looking
        crystal, and the way the much-to-be-pitied
        cocaine user is dragged slowly, but with
        aw ml certainty, down, toinsanitsand death
        is a terrible tribute to the strength ol the
        demon that links in ihe drug.
        This confusion oi ideas and language is
        the first symptom of the toxic influence of
        the cocaine beginning lo work. It you have
        a friend in whom these symptoms are no
        ticed, il might be well to find out il he is
        addicted 10 the use of cocaine, tor at this
        early stage the habit may be broken. Later
        it is almost hopeless for the victim to try
        to sunder his chains.
        Begun in many cases in a legitimate way,
        as an anesthetic, the surprisingly pleasant
        effect is sought, lor again by the one who has
        had a glimpse ai Ihe portals of elysium. This i
        is tbe beginning of the terrible habit. The i
        effect is a sense of exhilaration followed by a
        quiet, dreamy state that causes the worried
        man to forget his troubles and the sufferer i
        his pain. nn,.,. this freedom from physical
        and mental sickness has been experienced,
        the cocaine fiend will t 01. or kill to get the I
        ding. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093039/1911-05-12/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DANGERS Of DEADLY COCAINE
        Rapid Increase of the Most rnsidioiis Drug
        Habit—The Craving Usually Acquired by
        Accident
        With the month of May comes the
        opening of the six months harvest of
        the soda fountains. "What will you
        have?" asks the amiable clerk and
        points to a list of sirups, a row of gayly
        colored bottles and some large bowls on
        the counter containing crushed straw
        berries, sliced pineapple and other
        I tempting fruits. If you stick to the
        fruit sirups and the fruit is really good,
        no harm is done. On the contrary-
        But if you turn to the bottled attrac
        tions or listen to the promise of their
        much advertised qualities, then beware.
        Here is plain warning from Dr. L. F.
        Kebler, chief of the division of drugs
        in the government bureau of chemistry:
        "Attention is directed to the danger of
        soft drinks containing caSeine, extract
        of kola nut and extract of coca leaf, the
        active principle of the two latter being
        cocaine."
        According to Dr. Kebler, scores of
        soft drinks, dangerously medicated, are
        sold at soda water fountains as stimu
        lating and refreshing summer drinks
        without the slightest intimation to pur
        chasers that their stimulating and re
        freshing qualities come from cocaine, a
        drug that produces one of the worst
        habits known to the medical prefession.
        "We have seen," said Dr. Kebler,
        "how the opium habit may be acquired
        by the use of various proprietary or se
        cret preparations usually employed as
        domestic remedies, and so the cocaine
        habit may be developed by the use of
        these much lauded soft drinks."
        During a recent visit to Washington
        I talked with two heads of departments
        in the bureau of chemistry, both active
        in government prosecutions of drugged
        soda water sirups. "There is no ques
        tion," said one of these authorities,
        "that the presence of cocaine in soft
        drinks tends to create in the consumer,
        whether child or adult, a predisposition
        towards the cocaine habit."
        It is evident that the manufacturers
        of these soft drink sirups have only one
        motive for putting cocaine into them
        that is to make them popular, to make
        them taste good, to make them sell
        better. And this popularity, this pleas
        ant taste and better sale come simply
        and solely because there is enough co
        caine in these soft drinks to give some
        thing of the stimulating and exhilarat
        ing effect that cocaine always gives.
        "It is not uncommon," says Dr.
        Kebler, "to find persons addicted to the
        use of medicated soft drinks. It is a
        well known fact that many factory em
        ployes, stenographers, typewriters and
        others subject to mental or nervous
        strain spend a part of their earnings for
        drinks of this character. Parents, as a
        rule, withhold tea and coffee from their
        children; but, having knowledge of the
        presence of cocaine, caffeine or other
        deleterious agents in soft drinks, they
        unwittingly permit their children to be
        harmed by their use."
        Cocaine —what is it? The Standard
        Dictionary tells us: "Cocaine, a white,
        bitter, crystalline alkaloid contained in
        coca leaves; used in medicine as a
        local anesthetic." And again: "Coca,
        the dried leaves of a South American
        shrub of the flax family, used in medi
        cine as a tonic; chewed by tne native i
        Indians as a nervine stimulant." There
        is no connection between the coca
        shrub and the cocoa palm tree that pro
        duces cocoa nuts.
        An ounce containg 480 grains and a
        grain of cocaine is a dose. From a
        single source of cocaine supply in New
        York city 480,000 doses of this dan
        gerous drug were illegitimately dis
        pensed every month.
        How is the habit usually acquired?
        "By accident, like other drug habits.
        I'm sorry to say that one of these —er
        —accidents is the presence of cocaine
        in catarrh medicines." Dr. Podstata
        proceeded to give me details in the
        case of one of his patients, a man of 22,
        who became a cocaine fiend quite inno
        cently by taking a widely advertised
        "catarrh cure" that contained only a
        small percentage of cocaine, but, alas,
        enough to establish the habit. The
        young man sniffed his "catarrh cure"
        up his nose, and after each sniffing ex
        perienced a characteristic sense of ela
        tion, a peculiar well being. He took
        more and more of the stuff and soon
        {discovered that his exhilaration came
        from cocaine in the powder. Now, it
        was cocaine he wanted, not the catarrh
        cure; and presently he began to take
        the drug pure, sniffing it, after the man-
        i ncr of adepts and finally learning to use
        jit in hypodermic injections. Soon he j
        learned that the sensations were not at I
        all pleasant. Far from it! Quick after
        each period of intoxication came the
        i dread of reaction that calls for more and i
        always more cacaine. The character
        istic physical and moral deterioration
        went on rapidly. The victim grew sal
        low-faced, sunken-eyed, restless, irrita
        ble. He lost ambition and persever
        ance. He became a liar, a wreck, help
        less and useless, and within a year he
        was placed in an asylum.
        Notice that all this came to pass be
        cause a perfectly well-meaning young
        man bought at a reputable drug store
        in Chicago what was advertised as an j
        excellent cure for catarrh. And before
        he knew what he was doing and taking
        he had become a "coke fiend" and his
        life was irretrievably ruined.
        At Hull House, that haven of good
        works in Chicago, I found impressive
        corroboration of the statement that chil
        dren easily fall into the cocaine habit.
        Dr. Hamilton, a woman bacteriologist
        of Hull House, made an investigation
        among boys and young men in the
        neighborhood and found that numbers
        of them were regular users of the drug.
        Dr. Hamilton found that the cocaine
        habit had spread through one group of
        seven boys. The youngest,Willie, was
        coming home from school one day when
        a negro who offered him a sniff of pow
        der, saying it would make him feel
        good. Willie sniffed the powder and,
        as he expressed it, felt like a million
        aire. The negro sold him what was
        lelt of the powder in a little pill box
        for IS or 20 cents, and told the boy he
        would be around that corner every even
        ing with more of the stuff. He also
        suggested that Willie inform his boy
        friends of the wonderful effects of this
        powder. Willie went back to the cor
        ner and bought more of the drug. He
        wanted to feel like a millionaire. He
        told his two brothers, young men of 17
        and 18, and they tried the powder.
        One by one four of their friends were
        initiated until the group of seven was
        formed. All seven became absolutely
        demoralized; they quit going to school,
        stopped work, stayed away from home
        all night, going on regular cocaine de
        bauches and spending as much as $7
        in a single day for the drug. When
        their money gave out they would pawn
        their clothes, they would steal, they
        would do anything to get more money
        to buy more cocaine.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1912-12-04/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>DRUGGISTS DENOUCE COCAINE LAW LAXITY
                i easy matter to get the evldence against
                cocaine sellera?when he told how he
                had taken a ahort tlme to get a
                        j qualnted with the drug users in her
                        neighhorhood and had then been able
                        to bny It from Mrs. Fisher with their
                        introduction.
                        District Attorney Cropaey began hia
                        j iidive pursult of the cocaine sellers by
                        Interesting Deputy Commissioner
                        i Walsh in the matter. They intend to
                        keep after these lllegal merchants un
                        til they dean up Brooklyn.
                        We have already recelved reports
                        from wholesale houses that the sale of
                        the drug has been greatly redu. ed,"
                naid Mr. t'ropsey yesterday, "and lt is
                eartaJa that our flfty-elght convictlotiH
                have stirred up the tranVkers in co?
                caine ao that many of them are giving
                lt up as a bad Job to taekie in Brook?
                lyn."
                Urgea More Draatic Penalty.
                The District Attorney of King*
                County belleves the law should be
                made more drastlc, but declures re
                sults ii.ay eaelly be obttalned under
                the present law lf the police actually
                do the work they are supposed to do.
                "I belleve that an amendment mak
                lng the poasesston of cocaine, without
                n physl'ian'H preacription, a felony ln
                itself, without Inslstlng that the prose
                cution prove the possessor Intended to
                MU lt, would be a good addltion to the
                lnw. and I belleve the punlshment
                should be lncreased from the present
                llmlt of one year's lmprlaonment to
                something like flve years," he said.
                Mr. Cropsey thought that prison sen
                tences of some length were probably of
                more ubc ln curlng the vtctlms of the
                cocaine habit than any other possible
                retnedy.
                ln this connectlon the fsct standsout
                that one of the chlef things prison
                keepers have to contend with ln carlng
                for their prlsonera ls to keep them from
                obtalnli.g cocaine. Bo prevalent Is this
                habit among criminals that cocaine
                has even been sent bllndly Into filng
                Sing prison by outslders without any
                knowledge that lt would reach their
                own frlends wlthln.
                Warden Kenncdy, of Sing Sing. told
                a Tribune reporter re ently that on one
                                       occaslon he had bought a few eamp
                                       halrs neoeasary for extra a**ats In the
                ehapel. and though the transactlon was
                handled entlrely by the prison authorl
                ties. he thought of the poaslbillty of
                cocaine smuggllng, and had the chalrs
                carefully examlned on arrlval.
                Ha found each chair had had n smnll
                hole bored iu the woodwork. whleh had
                b.-en filled with cocaine. then carefully
                covercil up nnd vnrnished over. Inves
                tlgatlon ea to the source of this pros
                paettVO gift to the OOC-Joa users iii th?*
                prison had led nowliere, because the
                dealer who supplled the chalra could
                ot flnd at. what Btage of their handling
                the drug bad been hldden.
                Tlv warden aald hla guards had
                found cocaine hldden In the backa of
                ii alr brushes sent to convlets by friends
                OOtBlda. They had found lt even on
                poatenrda. where lt had been hldden in
                minute quantitlee under the stamp; in
                the mlddle of clgarettes sent In to mn
                victs, and even ln the hatbanda jf
                visitors who came to see them.
                l'ractically the same condltlona are
                true ln the prlaona on Blackwell's Isl?
                and, and even in the TombB, where
                men are not conflned for long periods.
                Taft Urgaa Congresa to Aet.
                The world-wlde peril in the growth
                of cocaine, oplum and other drug
                habit*, which was the reason for the
                calllng of a apeclal internatlonal con?
                ference on the aubject at The Hague
                last summer, recelved promlnent men
                tion ln Prealdent Taft's message to
                Congress yesterday. Bills are In pros
                pect in the preaent Congress over which
                both State and Treasury departments
                hav worked. and which will probably,
                aui.ng oth-r tbinge, put a ,_.-k to iu-1
                Idruggists denounce
                j cocaine law laxity</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1912-12-06/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>COCAINE BROUGHT IN
                BY STR1KE BREAKERS
                Former Chief City Food Inspector Says Cuban
                Negroes Intiroduced the Vice in
                New York.
                The "coke" habit is the coming evil of
                this country, unless strenuous and lmme
                dlatc measurefl are taken to suppress it,
                accordlng to Bayard C Fuller, who re
                tlred a year ago last Juiy as chlef food
                Inspector of the clty's Department of
                Health, after twenty yeara of eervlce in
                that department. For about flve yeara
                before hia retlrement. he aald yesterday,
                he made relentless war on the cocaine
                traffic ln this city, maklng between two
                hundred and three hundred arresta ln the
                last three years of that period.
                "Duiing lhat time," Mr. Fuller contln
                ued. "we made more arrests In a month,
                on the average. than the pollce did in a
                year. The two men who helped me moat
                ?and too great pralae cannot be be*tow*>d
                upon them for their stand in the inatter
                -were Maglstrate 'Joe' Corrigan and
                Matristrate 'Harry' Stclnert, new a Judge
                of Speclal Sesslons.
                "The habit flrst got a hold in this a number of years ago. when thero was
                a big strlke on the Ward llne of at. aniers
                and the company Imported negroes from
                JIavana to take the places of the strlkers.
                I wasn't chlef Inspector at that time, and
                mv duties used to take me down along
                the wharve*. where I would see these hlg
                blaek fellows lylng aiound hopelessly un?
                der the Influence of the drug.
                Negroea tha Diatributare.
                "They lntroduced it Into tho negro di?
                trlcts In the rlty, and from there It has
                spreud to the whltea. There Isn't a tough
                negro ln the city who doe?n't use It, and
                they are the one* who dlstribute It now.
                "The pollce. ln their present 'Ondltlon,
                are ab^olutely Ineapable of coplng wlth
                the sltuation, no matlt-r ho* BtrtagOllttha
                laws. You've got lo und^istand theeefel*
                lean to catrh them. They're all jealous
                and awapicloiis of one another i 4 of
                every one else, and thryil triek you to
                the laat degree If you don't know l.cw te
                handle them.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1914-02-15/ed-1/?sp=29&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>
                THE DRUG TERROR
                Drug dealers have
                grown prosperous
                on this type.
                With Practically
                Unrest ricted
                Traffic Cocaine
                Vice Has Grown
                So Swiftly That
                We Are Most
                Drugged Nation in
                World With 4.45
                Per Cent, of Popu
                lar on Addicted to
                Habit
                Hitting the Pipe."
                Tons of opium im
                ported for "medicinal
                purposes" are used
                for this purpose.
                Campaign Under
                taken by Mrs. Will
                iam K. Vanderbilt,
                Sr., for Extermina
                tion of Practice One
                of the Greatest
                Moral Struggles in
                History Cocaine
                and Heroin Dead-
                ?k lies t of Habit Form
                n r
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1914-02-15/ed-1/?sp=30&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>UNITED STATES MOST DRUG AFFLICTED OF NATIO
                DR. WILEY'S FAMOUS LIST OF DRUGGED MEDICINES.
                Published in Bulletin 393 issued by the Division of Drugs, Bureau of
                Chemistry, Department of Agriculture.
                Cocaine Bearing Medicines and Drinks.
                Dr. Birncy's Catarrh Powder
                Dr. Agnew's Catarrh Powder.
                Dr. Cole's Catarrh Cure
                Crown Catarrh Powder
                Tucker's Asthma Specific
                Koca Nola
                Celery Cola
                Wiscola
                Pillsbury's Koke
                Kola-Ade
                Kos-Kola
                Cafe-Cola
                Koke
                Coca-Bola
                Tobacco Bullets
                Wonder Workers
                Morphine Bearing Medicines.
                Strawberry and Pepsin Dr. Miller's Anodyne for Babies
                Kohlcr's One-Night Cough Cure
                Hooper's Anodyne, the Infants'
                Friend
                Dr. James's Soothing Syrup Cordial
                Yonkerman's Consumption Cure
                Shiloh's Cure
                Adamson's Botanic Cough Balsam
                Jadway's Elixir for Infants
                Antikamnia and Codein Tablets
                Ammonal with Codein and Camphor
                Royal Headache Tablets
                ?al-Codelu Bel
                Children's Comfort
                Kopp's Baby's Friend
                Mrs. VC'inslowV Soothing Syrup
                Gooch's Mexican Consumption Cure
                Dr. Grove's Anodvnc for Infants
                Dr. Fowler's
                Mixture
                Dr. A. Boschee'.s German Syrup
                Habitina
                Dr. Fenner's Cough Cold Syrup
                Prof. Hoff's Consumption Cure.
                Dr. MofTett's Tcethina, Teething
                Powders
                Dr. Bull's Cough Syrup
                Jackson's Magic Balsam
                Van Totta's Cough Pectoral
                Dr. Fahrney's Teething Syrup
                Linseed, Licorice and Chlorodyne
                Pastilles
                Ptitilles Panerai
                Dr. Fuhey's Pepsin AnoJyne Compound
                Cannabis Indica Bearing Medicines..
                Victor Infant Relief Piso's Cure, a remedy for Coughs and Colds
                Chloral Bearing Medicines.
                Davis';, Asthma Remedy Linseed, Licorice and Chlorodyne
                Acker's English Remedy Cough Lozenges
                than l consorting with wmb,
                The widespread net' of cocaine In
                tlie comparatively short period of
                time since It.i discovery," sas J)r.
                Towns, "has been brought about by
                patent preparations coutalr'ng small
                quantities of II."
                During Its tlrst few years cocaine nd
                illction spread through the wld" soli' of
                "catarrh cures." which contained from 2
                to 4 per cent, of cocaine. These "cures,"
                according to Samuel Hopkins Ad. mis In
                Ciilliri'i UVi'Afjr, were "Dr. Ilirncys Ca
                tarrh Cure," "Dr. Colo's Catarrh Cure."
                "Dr. Agnow's Caiairh Powder" and
                "Crown t 'atari li Powder." Not only did
                these "euro." Introduce many pcions
                Into depth of cocaine addiction, but
                they pointed the way to a method of j
                taking cocaine easier than by hypo- 1
                dermic.
                For u time It became the practice to
                fill Willi the "cure" a small bottle1
                through the cork of which had been In-M-r'etl
                it wo tubes, one of which was
                placed In the mouth and the other In
                the nostril; u puff from' the mouth did
                the rest. Later It became the custom to
                sprinkle the "cure" on. the back of the
                hand and either 'to touch It to the
                tongue or to sniff It onto the mucous
                membrane of the nostrils. Tims the
                deadliest of all vices became the Minplcsl
                to begin.
                Among the thousands who contracted
                cocaine addiction through the innocent
                putchase of a patent medicine was Mrs,
                Anna .Meyers, who was prominent
                socially In Chicago and In lsim was a
                member of the board of managers of
                the Chlcngo World's Fair. In a confes
                siou detailing the career of crime Into
                which cocaine plunged her Mrs. Meyers
                Mays: "I used to get the little boxes of
                the drug and call it 'my baby' and 'my
                only friend,' cry over It and laugh and
                dance like an Insane person."
                It Is asserted that per cent, of
                America's drug addicts learned their
                vice In a doctor's olllce. Hundreds of
                disreputable physicians make a practice
                of giving morphine promiscuously for
                their patients' iicIick, out of their olllees
                Issues a constant procession of young
                drill, addicts "Not more than 10 per
                cent, iif all the drug addicts have any
                incurable disease that would Justify fur
                ther use of the drug." says Dr. Towns.
                The use of drugs has crept Into colleges,
                where students take them tn counter
                act the effects of overwork; tfiey liavo
                crept Into the army, where soldiers take
                them ltd counteract the effects of under
                work. "Many great writer to use a
                current critical phrase," su's Dr. T. D.
                Crothers of Hartford, Conn., "begin the
                use of cocaine that they may whip their
                Inventiveness to action."
                Walters in restaurants use drugs to
                quicken their memory. It has been
                estimated that 1." per cent, of all the
                medical men in the United States are
                drug addicts, "One
                half of nil my drug
                patients ore physi
                cians," says Dr.
                Towns, who has u
                hill now pending at
                Albany, Introduced
                by Senator John .1.
                Itoylan, barring all
                drug addicted phy
                sicians from prac
                tice. School chil
                dren, even ut the
                ages of 7 and N. are
                offered cocnlne nnd
                horoln by pedlors
                about public school
                buildings. The Hull
                House campaign of
                l'.io.l started with
                the disc ivery thai
                certain negroes in
                Chicago Were stop
                ping school chil
                dren on the tilde
                walks and selling
                them a penny Ixoc
                of the deadliest
                habit forming drug
                In the world and
                asking them to "tell
                all their Hi t I e
                friends about It
                In that sect Inn
                of civilized society
                known as the under.
                World cocaine ad
                diction Is practically
                universal Cnderlts
                Intluetice ate most of
                the daring crimes
                committed. Most of
                the attacks tiMin
                white women of the
                South." says Dr
                Christopher Koch
                "are the tilled re
                suit of a cocaine
                crazed negro brain
                Thousands of dingy
                hovels are scattered
                tllloliuli ttle negro
                sections of Southern
                cities where "snow"
                is retailed In dime
                boxes through back
                doors which are
                prevented by chains
                from opening more
                than three Indies
                District Attor
                ney St. Clair estl
                m. les that In New
                Orleans nlone there
                nie 2.1,000 negro
                I calne addicts who
                p a t r o n i ze these
                I Joints, Overseers of
                Southern labor have
                been known to put
                cocaine Into their
                gang's rations in order to get more
                work out of them.
                As a result of the wide cocaine addic
                tion among negroes in the South Au
                gust llrahni cites figures to show that
                the negro race, which forms lu.T per
                cent, of the nation's population, com
                mits 37.12 per cent, of the murders.
                .1. IMgar llrown of Chicago </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059228/1914-06-03/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Clergyman Declares Cocaine Can BeWis.,,
                Bought as Easily as Ice Cream and [.last Saturday.
                Asserts That A States Should Have
                Uniform LawsTells of Effect of
                Drug on Victims.
                Hew York."There Is only one way
                to pat an end to the cocaine traffic in
                the United States, and that is to pass
                a comprehensive federal law which
                will regulate the sale, net only ef the
                harmful and obnoxious cocaine, but all
                drugs and narcotics that have vitiat
                ing qualities," aafd the Rev. James
                B. Curry of St. James' Soman Cotholie
                church when asked for his views on
                the war on habit forming drugs.
                Father Curry became interested in
                the fight on cocaine nine years ago, and
                he has been fighting it ever since. He
                is familiar with every phase of the
                matter
                "It is a matter that the federal gov
                ernment mast deal with sooner or
                later,' he said. "The widespread use
                of drop*, which is ruining the lives of
                thousands of men and women in this
                country and. most important of all.
                lives of thousands of boys and girls,
                makes it incumbent on the officials in
                Washington to take cognizance of this
                serious matter The time for procras
                tination is past, and we must get quick
                action.
                No individual state can successfully
                combat the evil For mstance. if New
                York state passes a drastic law regu- day.
                lating the sale of drugs it will be a
                -ample matter foe unscrupulous sellers
                of the drug to obtain, their supply in
                New Jersey or another state.
                'On some sides I have heard physi
                cians of this city criticised for filling
                prescriptions which enable the bearer*
                to obtain supplier of cocaine Rput
                bie physicians ore striving to lessen
                this evil to the best of their ability
                "I do think the wholesale drug
                houses are responsible for the spread
                ef this evil As an example of how
                easy it is to obtain cocaine and other
                harmful drugs from wholesale bouses,
                an acquaintance of mine recently in
                formed me that he could jret as much
                of the drag as be wanted without an
                order from a physician or anybody
                ifise I aSBL"* surprised that I re-1
                raestet him ttPmafce the effort.
                "He made out a list and mailed it to
                a drug bouse and asked for prices. In
                eluded In the list was cocaine In a
                few days he received the list with the
                prices filled in, and. checking off some*
                of the drugs, including cocaine, he re
                mailed the list Not long after that
                the goods were delivered, and the co
                eaine was in the order. It was as
                easy as buying ice cream.
                "It was in 1905 that I first took up
                the cudgels against the sellers of co
                caine I noticed sailors drifting over
                from the Bowery and patronizing- a
                certain druggist Before entering the
                store these men seemed to be down
                hearted and despondent, but coming
                out their manner had undergone a
                change They appeared to be animat
                ed and gleeful, cut up capers and seem
                ed pleased with everything in general.
                'I saw one of them, sniff cocaine one
                day I snt ceeded in obtaining some of
                the dni and sent It to the board of
                health for analysis, tt was found fa
                be 91) TA) per cent cocaine Subsequent
                ly the druggist was forced t close up.
                'Laws th.it esi* are not comprehen
                sive eno'ijili Some new drug springs
                up from time To rime and the present
                laws do not affect its ^ale-./ I propos*'
                that a l.iw be passed that will cover
                not onlv the drugs now regulated, but
                A. so new drugs that may come into ex
                istence A law can be so worded as to
                embra the new drugs and there will
                be no need for further legislation along
                thafhne
                Some persons have asked me where
                the cocaine habit originally came from.
                It is a hard question to answer, hut I
                really think that it came from the
                West Indies imagine that the negro?
                help on ships from the West Indies
                brought the habit to New York years
                ago."</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1914-06-06/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>THE STANDARD MAGAZINE SECTION OGDEN, UTAH
                I The greatest drug-using people
                In the -world are the American peo
                ple and not the Chinese. That Is
                the discovert of expert! working
                under the direction of Mrs. W. K
                Vanderbilt. Sr.. -vho. since January
                has been working against the use
                of drugs In the United States
                Today 4.1 per cent of the Chinese
                are drug users in some form. In
                America 4.45 per cent cf the popu
                lation uses drugs.
                Mrs Vanderbilt began her fight
                on the nation-wide use of drugs in
                the New York Legislature, where
                she fought for a bill prohibiting tho
                sale of cocaine, heroin and mor
                phine. She has given large sums of
                money to organizations opposing the
                drug habit In her efforts to obtain
                legislation against its sale
                The entire civilized world has
                been shouting about the horrors of
                the opium traffic of China. The
                Chinese were the originators of
                opium. It is believed. In China it
                was found 200 years ago that 6
                per cent of the people were drug
                victims. By consistent fighting
                against tho use of drugs; by laws
                limiting its manufacture and sale,
                the use of druj;s there has dropped
                to 4.1 per cent of the population in
                200 years.
                In America, however; the use of
                the drug is on the Increase.
                Laws preventing the transporta
                tion of cocaine from one State to
                another are sought by Mrs. Van
                derbilt, and in working for federal
                laws her experts have compiled
                data to show the enormity of the
                drug habit.
                Drugs are used by all classes. The
                criminal class Is addicted to Its use.
                Cocaine 1b Injected Into the aim.
                Opium la smoked and taken in oth
                er ways. Sometimes the drugs are
                snuffed. They are taken to drive
                away tho feeling of drowsiness
                sometimes. Country doctors ac
                quire the drug habit because of
                their long hours of work. They
                take drugs to keep themselves
                awake and take other drugs so they
                can go to Bleep quickly.
                Society women are known to take
                j drugs to drive away weariness in
                pursuing their social conquests.
                The terrible effects of taking
                eocaine have been pointed out time
                end again. In 1888 Dr. J. Howell
                Way wrote to the Medical News his
                experiences with cocaine.
                He Bald he Injected, one-quarter
                1 grain of cocaine in his forearm at
                j 6 p. m. Thirty minutee later he
                took a half grain. In ten minutes
                he became restless and his hreath
                lng was affected. In twenty min
                utes his pupils began to dilate.
                By 7 20 his condition was near
                collapse. By 7:30 he began to fear
                he would die. Cocaine was not as
                well known then as it is now. and
                Dr. Way took the drug simply as
                an experiment.
            </text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1915-05-22/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=cocaine+drug+narcotic+dope+pills+toxic+addict</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>DEPRIVED OTDOPE-CHME WAVE BEGINS
                Government Secret Service
                Agents In Desperate Battle With
                Drug Users Since Harrison
                Act Went Into Effect Fright
                ful Conditions Reported By
                U.,S. Officers In Making
                Numerous Raids
                U5E
                Is the Harrison anti-drug art tp
                oently passed by congress and In
                effect since March causing a crime
                wave bUUWt through the country:
                Will the more than a nullon drug
                users in the United States eventual
                ly turn desperate criminals to win
                the money that will buy drug at
                the present increased rate of the
                peddlers" There are indications of
                such a wave already
                While the government has been
                slow in the enforcement of this law
                because of a lack of deputy Internal
                revenue agents, whose duty it is to
                ferret out violations of the law, the
                effect of a partial enforce menl haB
                been felt throughout the country.
                In Nam York a number of people
                hae committed crimes to obtain
                money for drugs at an increased
                rate
                Several drug user6 have killed
                themselves because of the depriva
                tion while others have gone insane
                Practically the same results have
                been felt in Chicago, St Louis and
                other large cities,
                j In St. Louis several women have
                attempted suicide because they
                could not obtain the drugs and in
                Chicago a number of crimes have
                been tracexi to drug users
                The law. many complain, has
                placed an absolute ban on the sate
                of drugs to those addicted, but it
                has made no provision for the cure
                of the drug fiends.
                In the larger fities the hospitals
                established special wards 1
                these people might undergo a cure
                but the method itself was such a
                crude and cruel one that even phy
                sicians of repute themselves com
                plained. The enforcement of the
                law threw thebe new patients on
                their hands and they could not treat
                them without giving them soma
                drugs To break a man or woman
                in a day of a habit contracted in
                years might cause a fatal reaction
                of the heart, they said, and many
                of them went on record in opposi
                tion to the Harrison la
                In several hospitals the Lambert
                Townc treatment was used but with
                no great success, according to re
                ports. It was too severe and Caused
                many patients, willing to be cured,
                to leave the institution and go back
                to their old habits. It was baaed
                mostly on hyosciamine a derivative
                of opium but left the patient In an
                guish for more thai? 48 hours in th
                time the new drugs were battling
                the habit-forming alkaloids in his
                or her system.
                The few who underwent this
                treatment are said to have returned
                to their old haunt.-, and to have ro
                newed the use of drugs.
                i EFFECTS 01
                TREATMENT.
                The first effects of the Lambert
                Towne method was a dreadful nau
                iea in which thej were given prac
                tically no drugs and in which their
                systems were depended upon tu
                i light out the battle it w 18 an ex
                periment un the part of doctors.
                They had used the same i tire Jn
                I canes of delirium tremens with
                more or less success and thought It
                might conquer the drug habit.
                l when tb- Lambert-Townc method
                I was objected to they restored the
                old treatment of giving gradually
                reducing quantitiet ol drugs Tun
                bottles were arranged one with a
                I solution of the drugs to which the
                patient was addicted and the oth 1
                of a cure. As the patient took from
                the bottle containing the narcotic.
                i the amount was refilled from the
                bottle containing a cure until the
                drug bottle contained practically
                nothing but the cure</text>
        </result>

        <!-- Custom search query -->
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1904-08-21/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Italian+crime+police</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-06-23/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=drugs+raids+italian+squad</id>
            <rel>1</rel>
            <text>Acting over the heads of the Brook?
                lyn police, ihe Italian squad from Man
                hattan Headquarters raided two houses
                in Brooklyn early yesterday morning
                and confiscated $5.'.r>o,00i) 'worMi ot
                cocaine and several revolvers and stil
                ettos. They also arrested three men.
                two for having drugs in their posses
                sion and for violation oi the Sullivan
                law, and tiie third for murder in addi?
                tion to ;tie other eharges.
                The raids took place at about 5 a. m.
                Detective Sergcant Michael Fiaschet.ti
                and three other detectives first entered
                the home of Giovanni Mauro, fifty.
                three. at 160 Carroll Street. Here,
                they say, they found $175,000 worth of
                cocaine, ns well as a small arsenal of
                nistols and knives. Louis Mauro, son
                of Giovanni, was arrested with his
                father.
                The detectives then raided another
                house, at 170 Carroll Street, also said
                to he the property of Mauro, and found
                there Giuseppi Gangarossa, who, the
                police say, has been soutrht in connec?
                tion with the murder of Joseph Mes
                sina sinee Aprii 17, when the latter
                was slain in front of 17 Stanton Street
                in a quarrel over cocaine.
                The police say that Mauro admits
                purchasing the drug from sailors on
                merchant ships, who smuggled it inta
                the countrv.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1921-06-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Giuseppe+varotta</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-08-22/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Fiaschetti</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
        <result>
            <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1909-02-20/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Theodore+Bingham</id>
            <rel>0</rel>
        </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
